Michelangelo Pereira

Web Developer

michelangelo.ph@gmail.com 4168366720 michelangelopereira.com Surrey BC

I love helping people bring their designs to life. For the past three years I've been teaching coding and working on games. This has made it easy for me to start creating web pages and continue learning at velocity. I am now ready for a career making valuable contributions in web development with a tech company.

Education

Full Stack Web Development

Bloc 2017 - 2017

- •Programmed a digital music player with jQuery, javascript, HTML and CSS
- •Constructed the classic game of Pong with HTML5
- Created A Reddit clone built using Ruby on Rails
- •Made A collaborative HTML editing tool built with Meteor
- •Built a game portal + analytics service using Rails

Diploma Game Design

Vancouver Film School 2013 - 2014

- •Game Production
- •Business of Games
- Game Mechanics
- Level Design
- •Mobile & Social Game Design

Bachelor of Business Administration Marketing & Finance

Universidad Americana 2005 - 2009

- Marketing Channels and Logistics
- Market Research
- ·Consumer Behaviour
- Strategic Planning
- Production and Operations Management

Projects

Camp Roanoke

Dec 2013 - Apr 2014

Camp Roanoke is a 3D local multiplayer game hack-n-slash set in an eerie, neverending forest.• Worked closely with the lead programmer to design a system that created levels procedurally• Learned CG in order to

Experience

Senior Web Development and Unity 3D Instructor YSA Camp

Aug 2017 - Present Surrey

- •Lead two groups of four students in the creation of mobile apps for Android and iOS.
- Teaching python
- •Teaching kids to make android apps using MIT App Inventor
- •Teaching how to create a game using Unity 3D and Leap Motion for hand tracking
- •Taught kids to build and program Vex robots

Web Development, Adobe CC and Unity 3D Instructor YSA Camp

Jan 2017 - Jun 2017 Surrey BC

- •Taught how to use the Unity asset store and packages to create a 3D platformer.
- •Created scripts for managing levels, a checkpoint system and moving platforms.
- •Led students in the use of HTML, jQuery, Javascript, CSS and PHP.
- •Explained the use of Adobe After Effects, Illustrator, and Photoshop to
- •Used stock footage to create a holograph effect.
- •Showed students how to make a vector image of Super Mario out of simple shapes.
- •Used masks to create interesting composite images.

Coding Program Instuctor City of Surrey

Sep 2016 - Nov 2016 Surrey

Taught C++ and Scratch

Community Evangelist Steel Media Ltd

Apr 2016 - Jun 2016 Vancouver, Canada Area

- •Media partner and industry blog outreach and coordination
- •Post Secondary Technology and Design school, development agencies and development teams partnership activation.
- •Promotional and Event Ambassador: Locally offline; social media and blog online at national scale.

Some partnerships include: Apptamin, Mobile Growth Vancouver, WIGEH, Zennaapps, Newzoo, AC+A, Hardcore Indie, and Vancouver Unity Games

Instructor - Unity & Game Maker YSA Camp

Jan 2016 - May 2016 Surrey, BC

write shaders and work with the Lead artist to create a visually unique game• Programmed the game's HUD and menus using the NGUI plugin for Unity3D• Programmed all the games audio assets (over 200) using Audio Toolkit• Imported all of the games art assets and programmed all animations using Mecanim

Enlightenment

Jul 2013 - Sep 2013

Enlightenment is a 2D side-scrolling puzzle platform game in which the player plays as an eerie looking boy who uses a handheld flashlight to find a way out of the darkness of his grieving mind.• Used Flash and ActionScript 3 to program a 2D side-scrolling platformer• Programmed dynamic vectors in order to simulate a flashlight. Players could adjust their flashlight's intensity, turn it off or on, and widen or tighten their flashlight's aperture

Hat Jam

Aug 2013 - Aug 2013

A 48-hour game jam for VFS students, faculty, and alumni, held once every term (8 weeks).• Helped to organize and manage four game jams. Three took place at Vancouver Film School. The fourth was sponsored by Microsoft and took place at the Microsoft Development Center.• Helped track teams, register participants and write copy for the event

- •Computer Programming Evangelist, teaching children (age 8-15) fundamentals of computer programming
- •Developed lesson plans with objective to inspire and encourage creative and critical thinking skills
- •Facilitated classes, providing fun, interactive and engaging learning environment

Assistant Producer Adrian Crook & Associates

Feb 2015 - Nov 2015 Vancouver, Canada Area

- •Developed a comprehensive databases for target marketing campaigns
- •Compiled competitive analysis to launch new website design
- ·Social media and marketing coordinator
- •Content project manager streamlining editorial processes, adhering to deadlines, maintaining website, managing email database
- •Revitalized company's online presence by spearheading the creation of new case study pages to communicate services and successes.

Live Support VMC

Sep 2014 - Dec 2014 EA Canada

- •Community Support: providing live support for newly released games
- •Quality Analyst: documented bugs in original and localized game versions

Embedded QA VMC

Jul 2014 - Sep 2014 EA Canada

- •Played key role on FIFA 2015 release, the most successful FIFA demolaunch in EA history
- •Used DevTrack to write up, and regress bugs
- •Tested new builds of FIFA 15 for PS4, Xbox One, and PC daily

Unity 2D Mentor Vancouver Film School

Apr 2014 - Jul 2014

- Prepared and presented unity examples for how to use NGUI
- Showed students how to do object pooling for efficiency
- Explained Unity's particle system in depth
- Gave students 30 tips for game optimization